June 27th
この時間 ご覧のﾆｭｰｽを
お伝えしました｡
Before we go, here are the headlines again.
[ﾃﾚﾋﾞ]それでは 今日も一日
お元気に｡
We hope you have a great day.
Next up, News at 7.
[ﾃﾚﾋﾞ]続いては ﾆｭｰｽ ﾏﾙﾅﾅです｡
[ﾃﾚﾋﾞ]直接狙う 決めた！
He goes for the goal!
He scores!
The Japanese team have done it!
Japan Wins
やってくれました 日本代表｡
[ﾃﾚﾋﾞ]おはようございます
今日は ６月27日 金曜日｡
Good morning. Today is Friday, June 27th.
[ﾃﾚﾋﾞ]早速 ｻｯｶｰの話題から…｡
(咲太)んじゃ いってくるな｡
Let's start with soccer.
I'll be going, then.
(かえで)いってらっしゃい
お兄ちゃん｡
Have a nice day, Onii-chan.
日本代表 勝ったか｡
Japan won, huh?
Episode 4: No Tomorrow for Pigs
(国見)うっす 咲太
寝ぐせ立ってるぞ｡
'Sup, Sakuta. Some bedhead you've got there.
これは そういうﾍｱｽﾀｲﾙなんだよ｡
斬新だな｡
It's a hairstyle.
That's a new one.
おっ 双葉も うっす｡
(理央)おはよ…｡
And 'sup, Futaba.
Morning.
Japan won. Did you see the free kick in the first half?
日本代表 勝ったな｡
前半のﾌﾘｰｷｯｸ 見たか？
ああ 朝のﾆｭｰｽで見た｡
Yeah. I caught it on the morning news.
ｽﾎﾟｰﾂはｵﾝﾀｲﾑで見ないと
騒げないぞ｡
You gotta watch sports live.
It's more exciting that way.
そっか｡
Is it?
本当に作ったんだ｡
You really made me lunch?
Hey, I did it because you were being all sassy, like, "Can you even cook, Mai-san?"
(麻衣)咲太が ｢麻衣さんって
料理できんの？｣なんて
生意気なこと言うから
作ってきてあげたんでしょ｡
すみませんでした｡
僕が悪かったです｡
Okay, that was my bad.
生意気でした ごめんなさい｡
わかればいいのよ｡
I was too cheeky. Sorry.
As long as you understand.
いただきます｡
Let's eat.
Yes, let's.
あの… 麻衣さん｡
何よ？
Uh, Mai-san.
What?
好きです つきあってください｡
I love you. Please go out with me.
え 無視？
You're ignoring that?
After hearing that every day for a month,
I don't feel anything anymore.
１か月間 同じこと言われてると
何も感じなくなる｡
ときめかない｡
言わせておいて ひどいな｡
My heart doesn't skip a beat.
That's harsh. You're the one who made me say it.
そうだ ７月放送のﾄﾞﾗﾏに
出演が決まったの｡
Oh, right.
I've been cast in a TV show starting in July.
深夜枠で中盤の１話にだけ
登場する役なんだけどね｡
Though it's a late-night slot, and I'm only appearing in an episode in the middle.
ｷｽｼｰﾝもあるんだから｡
There's even a kiss scene.
My Neighbor,
the Whimsical Prince of Sweets
今 なんて？
ｷｽｼｰﾝがあるの｡
What did you just say?
There's a kiss scene.
Turn it down.
断ってください｡
いいじゃない｡
What's the big deal? Not like it'll be my first.
初めてってわけでもないし｡
ちょっと待った 麻衣さん
初めてじゃないって…｡
Hang on.
What do you mean, it won't be your first?
私のﾌｧｰｽﾄｷｽ 咲太にあげたの
覚えてないの？
Don't you remember how I gave you my first kiss?
My Neighbor,
the Whimsical Prince of Sweets
最低｡
え？ まさか
You're the worst.
My Neighbor,
the Whimsical Prince of Sweets
Huh? Was it when I'd forgotten about you?
僕が麻衣さんを忘れていた
あの間に？
おとぎ話みたいにはいかないわね｡
It doesn't work like in fairy tales, huh?
ｷｽをすれば 咲太が私のことを
I thought you'd remember me if I kissed you.
思い出してくれると
思ったんだけどな｡
必ず思い出すので
詳しい時間と場所を
Tell me when and where it happened.
I swear I'll remember it.
教えてください｡
嫌よ｡
No way.
At least give me a hint.
ﾋﾝﾄだけでも｡
絶対に教えない｡
Never.
そこをなんとか…｡
じゃあ…｡
Please!
Want to do it again, then?
もう一回する？
ぜひ…｡
I'd love to.
目を閉じて｡
Close your eyes.
いくわね｡
Here I go.
本当にされると思ったんだ｡
You really thought I'd do it?
麻衣さんと間接ｷｽができて
うれしいなぁ｡
I'm so happy I got to have an indirect kiss with you.
まっ 麻衣さんは大人だし
年下の僕と間接ｷｽするくらい
Well, I'm sure a mature lady such as yourself
would think nothing of indirectly kissing a younger boy.
なんともないんだろうけど｡
そ そうね｡
Th-That's right.
Just so you know, it's not me.
言っておくけど 私じゃないから｡
ん？
ｷｽｼｰﾝがあるのは主演の子｡
The kiss scene is for the lead actress.
麻衣さん 性格悪すぎ｡
You're a bully, you know that?
でも咲太は そんな私のことが
好きなんでしょ｡
But that's what you like about me, right?
さすがに このままだと
愛が冷めそう｡
I can feel myself falling out of love by the minute.
なっ なんでよ！
Wh-Why?
I mean, you don't seem interested at all.
だって 麻衣さん
全然その気なさそうだし
ときめかないとか言われると
絶望的な気分になる｡
And when you say you don't feel anything, it makes me lose all hope.
ﾀﾞﾒとは言ってない｡
Hey, I didn't say no.
Will you go out with me, then?
じゃあ いいの？
それは その…｡
Well, uh...
My
Neighbor,
the
Whimsical
Prince
of
Sweets
My Neighbor,
the
Whimsical
Prince
of
Sweets
My Neighbor,
the Whimsical Prince of Sweets
いいの？
Is that a yes?
My Neighbor,
the Whimsical Prince of Sweets
Yes.
My Neighbor,
the Whimsical Prince of Sweets
うん いいよ｡
My Neighbor,
the Whimsical Prince of Sweets
Let's go out.
What's gotten into you, Onii-chan?
どうしたんですか？ お兄ちゃん｡
何でもない｡
Nothing. It's just, waiting a month paid off.
１か月待ったかいが
あったってことだ｡
今日から 晴れて
僕と麻衣さんは…｡
Mai-san and I are now...
The Japanese team have done it!
Japan Wins
やってくれました 日本代表｡
[ﾃﾚﾋﾞ]おはようございます
今日は ６月27日 金曜日｡
Good morning. Today is Friday, June 27th.
June 27th
[ﾃﾚﾋﾞ]早速 ｻｯｶｰの話題から
いきたいと思います｡
Let's start with soccer.
どうしたんですか？ お兄ちゃん｡
なぁ かえで
What's the matter, Onii-chan?
Hey, Kaede. This may be a weird question, but...
ﾍﾝなこと聞くけどさ
このﾆｭｰｽ 昨日も見たよな？
Didn't we watch this same report yesterday?
えっと… 見てませんけど？
Uh... I know I didn't.
うっす 咲太 寝ぐせ立ってるぞ｡
これは そういう髪型なんだよ｡
'Sup, Sakuta. Some bedhead you've got there.
It's a hairstyle.
斬新だな｡ おっ 双葉も うっす｡
おはよ…｡
That's a new one.
And 'sup, Futaba.
Morning.
What's wrong, Sakuta?
どうした 咲太？
この会話 昨日もしなかったか？
Didn't we have the same conversation yesterday?
いや してないと思うぞ｡ なぁ？
Nah, I don't think we did.
Right?
してないね｡
だよな なら いいんだ｡
We didn't.
I guess not. Forget it.
《もしかして
僕だけってことか…》
Is it just me?
という数式から わかるわけだ｡
This formula will give you the solution.
《この授業も
This class,
あのﾜｲｼｬﾂの口紅の跡も…》
that lipstick on his shirt...
That's newlyweds for you.
重力加速度をﾊﾞﾊﾞｱ…
じゃなかった Ｇとした場合…｡
Let's refer to the gravitational acceleration as the G-Unit—
or rather, G—
...and the teacher's lame jokes
are all the same as yesterday.
《この寒いｷﾞｬｸﾞも昨日と同じ｡
今日が昨日ってことなら
If today is yesterday, then Mai-san and I aren't going out yet.
麻衣さんと僕も
まだつきあう前の段階｡
ってことは…》
Which means...
好きです つきあってください｡
I love you. Please go out with me.
１か月間 同じこと言われると
何も感じなくなる｡
After hearing that every day for a month,
I don't feel anything anymore.
ときめかない｡
そっか 失恋か｡
My heart doesn't skip a beat.
I see. I'm being rejected, huh?
じゃあ
新しい恋を探すしかないな｡
I guess I'll have to find a new love.
え？ ちょっ…｡
今まで ありがとうございました｡
Huh? Wai—
Thank you for everything.
ﾀﾞﾒとは言ってない｡
なに諦めようとしてるのよ｡
H-Hey, I didn't say no.
Why are you just giving up?
なら いいの？
Will you go out with me, then?
咲太のくせに生意気…｡
You're too cheeky, Sakuta.
いいの？
Is that a yes?
うん いいよ…｡
Yes. Let's go out.
ふぅ… これで問題なし｡
Okay. It's all good now.
(前沢)あのさ よかったら
俺とつきあわない？
Hey, what say you go out with me?
(朋絵)え？
(前沢)嫌かな？
You don't wanna?
い いえ その…｡
I-It's not like that.
(朋絵)あの…
少し考えさせてください｡
Um...
Give me some time to think about it.
Another budding romance, huh?
《こっちも告白か｡
僕も晴れて麻衣さんと恋人同士｡
Mai-san and I have become a couple, too.
あとは明日さえ来れば完璧》
Now as long as tomorrow comes, it'll all be perfect.
The Japanese team have done it!
[ﾃﾚﾋﾞ]やってくれました 日本代表｡
おはようございます
今日は ６月27日 金曜日｡
Japan Wins
Good morning. Today is Friday, June 27th.
[ﾃﾚﾋﾞ]早速 ｻｯｶｰの話題から
いきたいと思います｡
Let's start with soccer.
またか…｡
ん？
Not again.
何が またなんですか？
お兄ちゃん｡
What are you not-again-ing, Onii-chan?
June 27th
Nothing. Never mind.
いや なんでもない｡
これは双葉に相談だな｡
I'm gonna have to talk to Futaba about this.
(理央)梓川 それ 中２病だよ｡
Physics Prep Room
Azusagawa...
That only happens in children's imaginations.
僕は高２だ｡
なら 高２病でいいや｡
I think I'm past that age.
You've raised the bar to adolescents, then.
そうでなければ 梓川の大好きな
思春期症候群なんじゃないの｡
If not that, then maybe it's your beloved Puberty Syndrome again?
これっぽっちも好きじゃない｡
I don't love it at all.
てか なんとかしてくれ｡
明日が来なくて困ってるんだ｡
Do something about this.
Tomorrow just won't come. It sucks.
梓川が自分で
なんとかするしかないでしょ｡
You'll have to figure something out yourself.
私も含めて
その他70億人の人類は
The other seven billion people
on this planet, me included,
今日が３度目なんて
思ってないから｡
are not living today for the third time.
June 27th Repeating Third Time
Your search did not match any documents.
Please. Think of it as doing me a favor.
そこをなんとか
人助けと思って｡
梓川は 時間がﾙｰﾌﾟしてるって
言うけど
You say you're stuck in a time loop,
その考えには
とらわれないほうが
but you probably shouldn't be beholden to that idea.
いいんじゃない？
なんで？
Why not?
Because it's all kinds of hard to go back to the past.
過去に戻るのは
いろいろと大変だから｡
梓川が何度か経験した
６月27日は
The June 27th that you've
lived through multiple times
それより前の時間から
未来を見たものかもしれない｡
might just be you seeing it
from an earlier point in time.
過去に戻るのが大変なら
未来へ行くのは もっと大変だろ｡
If going to the past is hard,
shouldn't going to the future be even harder?
ﾀｲﾑﾄﾗﾍﾞﾙじゃなくて
未来予知って意味｡
I'm talking about precognition, not time travel.
いや 未来予知も
簡単じゃないだろ｡
Uh, that's not very simple either.
ﾗﾌﾟﾗｽの悪魔って 聞いたことない？
Have you ever heard of Laplace's demon?
あいにく
悪魔の知り合いはいないな｡
Sadly, I don't have any demonic acquaintances.
この世界に存在する
あらゆる物質は
All matter in this universe is equally bound under universal laws.
同じ物理法則の支配下に
平等である｡
その法則を数式化して
計算してしまえば
If you turn those laws into an equation that you can solve,
未来の状況を導き出せる｡
you can predict the future.
まるでﾋﾟﾝとこない｡
I'm not sure I follow.
つまり この世界に存在する
すべての原子の位置と
Long story short,
if one were to know the precise location and momentum of every atom in the universe,
運動量がわかれば…｡
未来の状況を 計算によって
導き出せるってことだよ｡
their future values could be calculated using the laws of classical mechanics.
すべての原子って すごい数だろ｡
Every atom in the universe?
That's an astronomical number.
うん 膨大なﾃﾞｰﾀを
数式で計算するとなれば
Yeah.
Running all that data through an equation would require considerable time.
それ相応の時間が必要となる｡
１秒後の未来を計算するのに
１秒以上かかったんじゃ
It'd be pointless to calculate one second into the future if it took more than a second to do so.
意味がない｡
だよな｡
Right?
だから そんな途方もない
真似ができる
So a physicist, Laplace, came up with a fictional being who could do that.
空想上の存在を
物理学者のﾗﾌﾟﾗｽさんは
考え出した｡
それがﾗﾌﾟﾗｽの悪魔か｡
And that's Laplace's demon, huh?
その悪魔には
一瞬で この世界に存在する
It has the ability to know the location
and momentum of every atom in existence
すべての原子の位置と運動量を
把握する力があって
and can calculate the future in an instant.
瞬時に未来を計算できる｡
僕が今 見ているのも
そうやって計算した未来だと？
And what I'm living now is a
calculation of the future too?
そう｡
悪いが 僕は
Right.
I hate to break it to you,
but I'm not some shady demon.
そんな怪しげな悪魔じゃないぞ｡
だったら 本物のﾗﾌﾟﾗｽの悪魔を
捜すんだね｡
Then you'll have to find the real Laplace's demon.
And how do I do that?
どうやって？
悪魔だけは
The demon is likely the only one aware of the looping June 27th
繰り返される６月27日の記憶を
持ったまま
前回とは違う行動を
とってる可能性が
and therefore the only one acting differently from loop to loop.
高いんじゃない？
《前回と違った行動を
とってるやつ…》
Someone acting differently from previous loops...
重力加速度をﾊﾞﾊﾞｱ…｡
Let's refer to the gravitational acceleration—
How the hell am I supposed to pick them out
from the seven billion people in this world?
《そんなの 全世界70億いる
人類の中から
見つけられるわけないだろ｡
麻衣さんとのお昼の時間だけが
唯一の癒やしだよな…》
Lunchtime with Mai-san is my only solace.
いたよ ﾗﾌﾟﾗｽの悪魔｡
Wow, I actually found Laplace's demon.
梓川先輩… だよね？
You're Azusagawa-senpai, right?
梓川咲太 ２年生｡
古賀朋絵 １年生… です｡
Azusagawa Sakuta, second-year.
Koga Tomoe, first-year. Pleased to meet you.
ﾀﾒ口でいい
尻を蹴り合った仲なんだし｡
No need to be so formal.
We're butt-kicking buddies.
それ 忘れて！
古賀 つかぬことを聞くが｡
Forget about that!
Koga, can I ask you something random?
何？
今日は何度目だ？
What?
How many times does today make?
It's my third time.
僕は３度目だ｡
It's my third time too.
私も３度目…｡
私だけじゃなかったんだ｡
So it wasn't just me.
何なの？ これ
この先 どげんなると？
What's happening?
What's gonna become of me?
Teenage Pig Doesn't
Dream of Bunny Girls
一応 聞くけど
古賀に心当たりはないのか？
Just to be sure, do you have any idea why this might be happening?
いっちょんわからん｡
何だって？
Not an inklin'.
Say what?
あっ… ぜ 全然わかんない｡
N-No idea.
使えねえ｡
それ 先輩じゃん！
Useless.
Right back at you!
なんか最近 嫌なこととか
悩んでることないか？
Did something bad happen recently? Is there anything troubling you?
なんで そんなこと
先輩に言わないといけないの？
Why should I have to tell you that?
あっ ﾒｯｾｰｼﾞ｡
(受信音)
Oh, I've got a message.
Because I'm pretty sure
Puberty Syndrome is involved here.
この状況
思春期症候群だと思うからな｡
古賀の思春期特有の
不安定な精神が
If a classic teenage instability of yours is what's behind this,
引き起こしている状況なら
その原因を究明して
解消するしかない｡
then we'll have to figure out
the cause and resolve it.
思春期症候群って 先輩 正気？
Puberty Syndrome? Are you serious, Senpai?
そんなのﾈｯﾄのうわさじゃん｡
That's just an online rumor.
Stop doing that while you're talking to me.
てか 話してる最中は やめろ｡
返してよ！
Hey, give it back!
話しながらは しないから！
Okay, I won't text and talk at the same time!
ほれ｡
Here.
話すほうをやめんのか？
気が散る 話しかけないで｡
So you chose to stop talking?
Quiet. You're distracting me.
すげえな 女子高生｡
High school girls are something else.
で なに？
最近 嫌なこととか
Okay, where were we?
Did something bad happen recently?
Is there anything troubling you?
悩んでることはないか？
That might be a hint to getting past June 27th.
６月27日を抜け出すﾋﾝﾄが
そこにあるかもしれない｡
I've put on some weight.
少し太った｡
大丈夫だ｡
That's okay. If anything, you're too thin.
古賀は むしろ痩せている｡
It'd do you good to gain some weight,
especially around the chest area.
少し太って
そのぺったんこな胸に
肉をつけたほうがいいくらいだ｡
全部 お尻とお腹にいくから
It all goes to my waist and butt!
That's why it sucks!
困ってるの｡
(足音)
あっ 隠れて！
おっ｡
H-Hide!
Is he looking for you?
古賀を捜してるんじゃないのか？
そうだと思うけど
Probably, but I texted him and said I had something to do over lunch break.
昼休みは用事がある的な
ﾒｯｾｰｼﾞを送っちゃったし｡
ﾊｧ…｡
いいから さっさと
Just go let him ask you out.
告白されてこい｡
なして 告白のこと知っとおと？
How'd ya know 'bout that?
I saw it last time.
前回 見たんだよ｡ そもそも
なんで隠れる必要があるんだ？
Why do you even need to hide from him?
だって 前沢先輩は
玲奈ちゃんの憧れの人なんだよ？
Because Maesawa-senpai is Rena-chan's crush.
はぁ？
ｸﾗｽの友達 香芝玲奈ちゃん｡
What?
Kashiba Rena. My friend in class.
よく一緒に ﾊﾞｽｹ部の練習を
見に行ってたの｡
We often went together to watch the basketball team practice.
(朋絵)玲奈ちゃんが
｢前沢先輩かっこいい！｣って
Rena-chan said she thought
Maesawa-senpai was hot,
言ってて 私は それに
付き添ってただけなんだけど｡
and I was only tagging along with her...
古賀のほうが気に入られたと？
う うん｡
But he took a liking to you instead?
Y-Yeah.
お前も その人のこと好きなわけ？
ううん｡
Do you like him back?
Nah. I ain't got a thing for the popular sorts.
ﾓﾃそうな人は いっちょん好かん｡
Then why don't you just let him ask you out and turn him down?
だったら さっさと告白されて
ふればいいだろ｡
そんなことしたら
絶対にｸﾗｽでﾊﾌﾞられる！
But if I did, I'd definitely become the class outcast!
玲奈ちゃんの…
友達の好きな人なんだよ｡
Rena-chan... My friend has a crush on him, y'know?
なのに 私が告白されるとか
空気読めてなさすぎ！
How am I supposed to let him ask me out?
I'm not that clueless!
大声出すとﾊﾞﾚる｡
Keep it down. He'll hear you.
用事って これかよ
男の趣味 悪っ｡
So "something to do" meant someone to do, huh?
Damn, you have awful taste.
いや 違い…｡
あっ あっ…｡
No, it's not—
これは誤解です｡
This isn't what it looks like.
待って 麻衣さん
説明をさせてください！
Wait, Mai-san!
Let me explain!
話しかけないで｡
Don't talk to me.
Whatever.
まっ いっか どうせ明日も
今日をやり直すんだろうしな｡
It'll all be reset tomorrow, anyway.
Good morning.
Whodunnit?!
おはようございます
今日は ６月28日 土曜日｡
Today is Saturday, June 28th.
[ﾃﾚﾋﾞ]驚きのﾆｭｰｽから
お伝えしたいと思います｡
Let's start with this shocking report.
June 28th
どうかしましたか？ お兄ちゃん｡
かえで
What's the matter, Onii-chan?
Kaede, please pinch my cheek for me.
僕のほっぺたをつねってくれ｡
はい わかりました｡
Sure thing.
痛いな｡
Okay, that hurts.
What do you want on this fine Saturday morning?
土曜の朝っぱらから なに？
[℡]ﾀｲﾑﾏｼﾝを作ってくれ｡
Build me a time machine.
切っていい？
僕はいたって大まじめだ｡
Can I hang up now?
I'm completely serious.
[℡]今 着替え中なんだけど｡
I'm getting dressed here.
具体的に どんな状況か
教えてくれ｡
Tell me more. What stage are you at?
[℡]あと靴下をはくだけ｡
変わった順番で着替えるのな｡
Just need to slip on my socks.
Socks last? That's a strange order.
普通でしょ で 用件は？
It's normal.
So what do you want?
[℡]昨日 相談したこと
覚えてるよな？
Remember the talk yesterday
about being stuck in the same day?
[℡]同じ日を繰り返してるってやつ｡
おめでと｡
Congrats.
[℡]昨日を脱出できたんだ｡
不本意なかたちでな｡
You made it out of yesterday like you wanted.
I did want it, but not like this.
[℡]それじゃ 私 靴下はくから｡
(通話が切れる音)
I'm putting on my socks. Bye.
僕は靴下以下か｡
Socks are more important than me?
《とにかく
昨日が もう来ないなら
Anyway, if I can't go back to yesterday,
I'll have to clear the air with Mai-san and have her forgive me.
麻衣さんの誤解を解いて
許してもらうしかない》
桜島さん？ 今日は来てないよ｡
え？
Sakurajima-san? She's absent today.
じゃあ その１年の古賀さんが
ﾗﾌﾟﾗｽの悪魔だったってわけね｡
That means the first-year, Koga-san, was Laplace's demon.
告白がなくなったことで
古賀を悩ませていた問題は
She avoided being asked out,
and that resolved her immediate problem.
解決したわけだからな｡
何かあったのか？
なんで？
Did something happen?
Why do you ask?
機嫌悪そうだから｡
ﾊｧ…｡
You seem down.
まっ １人で悶々としてるよりは
I guess it'd be better to tell you and make you laugh
instead of keeping it all inside.
梓川に話して
笑ってもらったほうがいいか｡
なんだ そりゃ｡
今朝 国見と電車で一緒になった｡
What the heck?
I was on the same train as Kunimi this morning.
それで？
べつに どうも｡
And?
Nothing.
彼女持ちの男子に
声をかけられて
I'm just disgusted at myself for being happy when a guy with a girlfriend talked to me.
うれしいとか思ってる自分に
嫌気がさしてるだけ｡
そりゃまた 乙女ﾁｯｸな悩みだな｡
How very girly of you.
梓川に声をかけられても
虫ずが走るだけなのにね｡
Meanwhile, when you talk to me,
it only makes my skin crawl.
その一言 必要だったか？
Did you have to say that part?
なんか私 ますます
ﾀﾞﾒになってるかも｡
I get the feeling I'm getting worse and worse.
いっそ 言ったらどうだ？
何を？
Why not just tell him?
Tell him what?
好きだって｡
今は正論なんて聞きたくない｡
That you like him.
That makes too much sense.
You should clear things up before they get any worse.
それ以上こじらせる前に
はっきりさせたほうが
いいと思うぞ｡
さっさと告白して 玉砕してこい｡
Tell him how you feel
and have him reject you.
それが原因で 私まで
ﾗﾌﾟﾗｽの悪魔になったら
But what if that turns me
into Laplace's demon too?
梓川は収拾つかなくなるよ｡
You'll go back to square one.
まっ 僕のほうは とりあえず
昨日を脱出できたわけだから
Well, I did manage to get out of yesterday.
あとは麻衣さんの誤解さえ解けば
万事解決だけどな｡
Now if I can just clear things up with Mai-san,
everything will be okay.
誤解が解けたら
その前沢って先輩は
But if you clear that up,
won't Maesawa-senpai ask Koga-san out again?
また古賀さんに
告白するんじゃない？
え？
誤解が解けなかったとしても
Even if you don't, he'll notice his misunderstanding soon enough.
すぐに勘違いに気づくでしょ｡
そもそも梓川は １か月前に
全校生徒の目の前で
You let the entire school know that you love Sakurajima-senpai just a month ago.
桜島先輩に
告白してるわけなんだし｡
あ… そうなったら また
昨日から やり直し？
Then I'll be thrown back to yesterday again?
その可能性は高いだろうね｡
That's quite likely.
つまり どうやっても 麻衣さんと
おつきあいできる明日は
So a future where I can go out with Mai-san won't come, no matter what?
やってこない…｡
梓川 そういう状態を
Azusagawa, do you know what that is called?
なんていうか知ってる？
詰みだな｡
Checkmate.
ﾊｧ…｡
どうした？ 咲太｡
What's wrong, Sakuta? Your eyes look dead.
目が死んでるぞ｡
ちょっと ２人ともいいかな？
Got a moment, you two?
今日から
入ってもらうことになった
This is Koga-san. She'll be joining us from today.
古賀さん｡
ﾌﾛｱの仕事 教えてあげてね｡
Show her the ropes around the floor, will you?
古賀!?
あっ 先輩！
Koga?
Senpai!
あ～ 学校同じ？
それじゃ ﾎﾝﾄの後輩ってことで
Oh, you go to the same school?
Then please look out for her,
as her senior in more ways than one.
いろいろ面倒をみてあげて｡
こ 古賀朋絵です｡
よろしくお願いします｡
I-I'm Koga Tomoe. Nice to meet you.
俺は 国見佑真｡
そういや 前に
I'm Kunimi Yuuma.
Oh, yeah. Didn't you two kick each other's butts or something?
尻を蹴り合った仲とか
言ってたよな｡
なんで人に話すの!?
あんなおもしろいこと
Why are you telling people?!
It'd be a waste to keep
such a funny story to myself.
黙ってたら もったいないだろ｡
Azusagawa-kun.
梓川くん ７番ﾃｰﾌﾞﾙ ｵｰﾀﾞｰお願い｡
Take Table 7's order, please.
On it.
わかりました｡
...I hear.
(亜矢)らしくてさ｡
(日南子)えっ そうなの？
What? Really?
(玲奈)だから来たんでしょ｡
ご注文は お決まりですか？
That's why we're here.
Are you ready to order?
あ？
朋絵のこと 本気なんですか？
Do you really have feelings for Tomoe?
すみません 当店では
ﾄﾓｴﾉｺﾄ ﾎﾝｷﾅﾝﾃﾞｽｶは
I'm sorry. "Do you really have feelings for Tomoe" is not on our menu.
扱っていないもので｡
まじめに聞いてるんですけど！
I'm asking a serious question here!
(亜矢)桜島先輩にふられて
すぐだから 心配してるんです｡
We're worried because it happened soon after you got rejected by Sakurajima-senpai.
(日南子)朋絵 確かにかわいいけど
どこがよかったんですか？
Sure, Tomoe's really cute,
but what else do you like about her?
なんか勘違いしてるぞ たぶん｡
You seem to have the wrong idea about something.
You don't have to hide it. We already know.
隠さなくても もう知ってますよ｡
あっ 朋絵 いたよ｡
There's Tomoe.
やっほ～｡
Yoohoo.
Rena-chan, you guys! You really made it!
玲奈ちゃん みんなも｡
ﾎﾝﾄに来てくれたの？
絶対に行くって言ったじゃん｡
制服かわいい｡
We did promise to come.
That's a cute uniform.
うん かわいい｡
Yeah, you look great.
Senpai, if you're just messing around with Tomoe, you'll have hell to pay.
先輩 朋絵のこと遊びなら
許しませんよ｡
Senpai, I need a favor!
先輩 実は先輩にお願いが！
断る｡
I refuse.
せめて話を聞いてよ｡
聞くのを断る｡
At least hear me out!
I refuse to listen.
なしてぇ？
大方 僕と古賀が
But why?
You want me to keep quiet and let people think that you and I are dating, right?
つきあってる的な誤解を
そのままにしてほしいとか
言うんだろ？
先輩 心が読めるとね!?
Are ya a mind reader?!
Don't you have other things to worry about?
てか もっと
気にすることがあるだろ｡
思春期症候群のこと｡
それは 今日になったから
Like your Puberty Syndrome?
We made it to today,
so that doesn't matter anymore.
もういいじゃん｡
今は それどころじゃないの｡
I've got bigger problems now! I'm in big trouble!
ﾋﾟﾝﾁなの！
だいたい誤解をそのままにって
How long do you want me to let people have the wrong idea, anyway?
いつまでだよ｡ まさか
３年生が卒業するまでか？
Surely not until the third-years graduate?
そこは ちゃんと考えてきたよ｡
I do have a plan for that.
誤解してもらうのは
１学期の間だけだから｡ お願い！
They just have to think we're dating until first term ends, so please!
夏休みになっちゃえば
学校もないし
There won't be any school over summer break,
その間に関係が
うやむやになったことにすれば
so we can say things fell apart then.
２学期は 普通にできるでしょ？
ﾊｧ…｡
That way, we can go back to normal in second term.
Hey, Senpai!
ねぇ 先輩！
自分で言うのもなんだけど
学校内の評判が最悪な僕と
I know I'm not one to talk,
but do you really wanna pretend-date
the guy with the worst reputation in school?
つきあってる的なことにするのは
いいのか？
最近の先輩 １年生の間じゃ
Actually, you've gone full circle and reached dateable status among the first-years lately.
１周回って
ｱﾘってことになってるから
平気だと思う｡
なんだ そりゃ｡
I think it'll be fine.
What the hell?
ｸﾞﾗｳﾝﾄﾞの中心で愛を叫ぶなんて
普通 ありえないし｡
It's not every day that a guy screams about
his love in the center of the school ground.
ああいうの ちょっと憧れる｡
It's kinda sweet.
古賀には 絶対しないけどな｡
ん～｡
I'd never do that for you.
あっそうだ つきあってるだと
急すぎるから
Oh, right.
It'd be too sudden to say we're dating,
so let's go with something more gradual.
その手前くらいがいいな｡
先輩以上恋人未満的な？
Like, "more than schoolmates, less than lovers"?
お前さ 自分が
何をしようとしているか
Look, do you realize what you're trying to do?
わかってるのか？ 全校生徒に
ｳｿをつくってことだぞ｡
You'll be lying to the entire school, you know?
I know that.
わかってるよ そんなこと｡
とにかく お願い！
Please just help me.
I lived in Fukuoka until middle school.
私 中学までは福岡で
こっちには
高校からの友達しかいないの｡
My friends from high school
are the only ones I have here.
さっきの３人か｡
そう｡
Those three earlier?
Yeah.
And if I don't do something,
I'll become the class outcast.
このままだと 私 ｸﾗｽに
居場所なくなっちゃう｡
休み時間も ひとりで
お弁当も ひとりで食べて
I'll be alone during recess and have to eat alone.
ﾄｲﾚも ひとりで行くのは嫌｡
I don't wanna go to the washroom alone either.
Please go to the washroom alone.
ﾄｲﾚは ひとりで行けよ｡
無理｡
No way.
ひとりはひとりで楽だぞ｡
Being alone has its benefits, you know.
周囲に合わせる必要ないし
You don't have to try to fit in,
なってみれば 思ったほど
寂しいとは感じない｡
and it's not as lonely as you'd think.
べつに寂しいから
嫌なわけじゃないし｡
It's not like I'm worried about being lonely.
はぁ？ なら なんだよ？
What? Then what's the problem?
ひとりは… 恥ずかしい｡
Being alone is shameful.
みんなから ｱｲﾂ
いつもひとりだって
I don't want people looking at me and going,
"Oh, she's always alone."
思われるのは 嫌｡
⦅嫌… 学校行くの恥ずかしい⦆
No...
I'm too ashamed to go to school.
先輩？
わかった｡
Senpai?
Okay, fine.
全校生徒にｳｿをついてやるよ｡
ﾎﾝﾄに!?
I'll lie to the entire school for you.
Really?
ああ｡
それじゃ もう一つお願い｡
Yeah.
In that case, I have one more favor to ask.
あ 明日なんだけど
先輩 ﾊﾞｲﾄ終わったあと ﾃﾞ ﾃﾞ…｡
T-Tomorrow, after you're done with work...
D-D-D...
ﾃﾞｺﾋﾟﾝだな｡
違う！
Ding your forehead?
No!
Go on a d-date with me!
ﾃﾞ ﾃﾞｰﾄして！
なぜだ？
Why?
玲奈ちゃんに ｢ﾃﾞｰﾄはしないの？｣
って聞かれて｡
Rena-chan asked me if we're not going to go on dates or anything.
Just lie to her and say you had a great time
over the weekend or something.
そんなの適当に ｢あ～ 週末は
ﾊｯｽﾙした！｣ って
ごまかせばいいだろ｡
念のため 写真を撮っておきたい｡
I wanna take pictures, just in case she asks.
お前 意外と ぬかりないな｡
Wow, you're surprisingly thorough.
《麻衣さんには
どう伝えたものか…｡
What am I supposed to tell Mai-san?
きっと必死に弁解する僕を見て
I bet she'll smile happily as I grovel before her.
心底楽しそうに笑うだろうな…》
Damn, that sounds fun.
やべえ すげえ楽しそう｡
As the last week of June draws to a close, a hot summer is right around the corner.
[ﾃﾚﾋﾞ]さて ６月も今週で終わり
そろそろ暑い季節がやってきます｡
お天気はｺﾏｰｼｬﾙのあと
Stick around, because after this break,
Sakiyama-san will have the forecast for us.
気象予報士の咲山さんが
詳しく解説します｡
あっ お兄ちゃん この人
Look, Onii-chan! Isn't that the girl you brought home before?
前に お兄ちゃんが
連れてきた人ですよね？
一口あげよっか？
Want a sip?
やっぱﾀﾞﾒ！
Actually, I changed my mind.
Yeah, that's her.
ああ そうだな｡
(ｲﾝﾀｰﾎﾝ)
Who is it, so late at night?
なんだ？ こんな時間に｡
はい｡
Yes?
It's me.
私｡
どうして 言い訳しに来ないのよ？
Why won't you come explain yourself to me?
That's Azusagawa for you. Filthy pig.
Next Episode
#5: Wishing You All the Lies in the World